## Arta Khosravi she/Her

universe through cutting-edge research.

**(**+98) 902 200 8277

• artakh10

**∠** artakh10@gmail.com

★ Tehran, Iran | Persian
♦ Arta Khosravi
in Arta Khosravi

With a Master of Science degree in Gravity and Cosmology, my research interests encompass Accretion Disks, Active Galactic Nuclei, Dark Energy and Dark Matter, Black Hole Cosmology, Epoch of Re-ionization, and Negative mass cosmology. As a Research Assistant with more than two years of experience, I am dedicated to advancing our understanding of the

### **Education**

### **m** Shahid Beheshti University

2021 - 2023

M.Sc of Gravity and Cosmology

Tehran, Iran

- Thesis Title: Negative Mass Cosmology with SNIa and BAO Data.
- · Supervisors: Prof. Marzieh Farhang, Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- Thesis Grade: OutstandingOverall GPA: 14.89/20

## **m** Shahid Beheshti University

2016 - 2021

B.Sc of Physics

Tehran, Iran

- Overall GPA: 15.49/20 (GPA of last year: 17.92) Final Projects:
- · Thesis title: Exoplanets and Habitable Zones
- · Supervisor: Prof. Nima Khosravi
- · Importance of Quasars for Dark Energy properties: during the Cosmology Undergraduate course

## **Research Experience**

## m PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

Jan. 2023 – Present

Research Assistant

Tehran, Iran

> Working on "On the Accretion Efficiency of High Redshift Quasars based on the QUOTAS & QuasarNet Data set". (Paper is in preparation.)

Using Data Analysis and Machine Learning to Investigate the Relations between *Black Hole Accretion Rate* and Super Massive Black Hole Mass, Bolometric Luminosity, Radiation Rate,  $\lambda L_{\lambda}$  or specifically  $L_{5100}$ , Eddington Ratio ( $\lambda_{edd}$ ) and Redshift Using QUOTAS Data and to find the best fit with logical parameters.

## m PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

Jan. 2023 – Present

Research Assistant

Tehran, Iran

> Worked on rotating Black Hole's Spin Effect on Black Hole Accretion Rate.

Using Data Analysis via Python to Investigate whether a rotating BH's Spin (a) can affect BH's Accretion efficiency or not.

### m PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Research Assistant Intern

Tehran, Iran

> Worked on Thermal Evolution from 21cm emission.

Using Data Analysis via Python to solve the Thermal evolution equation from 21cm heating, Ly $\alpha$  heating, and X-ray heating; and Investigating the relation between  $T_k$  and  $T_{spin}$  with Redshift using 21CMSOLVER code.

## **m** Shahid Beheshti University

Jun. 2022 – Present Tehran. Iran

Research Assistant

## > M.Sc. Thesis Title: Negative Mass Cosmology with SNIa and BAO Data.

- > Abstract: The Thesis presents the concept of negative mass in the cosmological model. We explore the potential impact of negative mass on the acceleration of the universe's expansion and its role as a component of the cosmos. The study aims to determine if the cosmological constant and cold dark matter can assume negative values within this model. A novel model is proposed to explain the observed positive acceleration of the cosmos in terms of the Hubble parameter while discounting certain characteristics. The model is tested using type Ia supernovae and baryon acoustic oscillations data, revealing two scenarios for obtaining the best values of cosmic parameters. It is important to note that this project does not investigate the negative mass cluster.
- > Supervisors: Prof. Marzieh Farhang, Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- > Future Aspects Include: Investigating the effects of Negative mass and comparing the data by adding another set of parameters Using MCMC.

### **m** Shahid Beheshti University

Research Assistant

Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020 Tehran, Iran

### » B.Sc. Thesis Title: Exoplanets and Habitable Zones.

- > Supervisor: Prof. Nima Khosravi
- > Abstract: Exoplanets are planets that orbit stars other than the sun, offering valuable information about planetary formation, evolution, and the possibility of extraterrestrial life. Despite challenges in detection and characterization, the study of exoplanets is crucial for understanding their significance to Earth and exploring potential habitable zones.

### Publications

# A. Khosravi, S.S. Tabasi, A. Karamzadeh, J.T. Firoozjaei, "On the Accretion Efficiency of High Redshift Quasars based on the QUOTAS & QuasarNet Data set"

> Under preparation.

## Teaching Assistant Experience

## **m** Shahid Beheshti University

Feb. 2023 – Jun. 2023

Tehran, Iran

- Teacher AssistantCourse: Cosmology (I) for Graduate Students
- > Reference: Cosmology by Daniel Baumann
- > Lecturer: Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- > Highlights: Responsible for holding exercise classes, Designing computational exercises using Python and Mathematica, preparing students, recitations, and grading homework.

## Workshops, Seminars, and Meetings

Cosmology: From Theory to Observation	Aug. 2023
Institude for Research in Fundamental Sciences (IPM)	Tehran, Iran
Cosmology and Astrophysics with New Data	Jul. 2022
K. N. Toosi University of Technology	Tehran, Iran
Machine Learning and Physics	June. 2022
SciSchool Institude	Tehran, Iran
Statistical Analysis of Cosmic Fields	Oct. 2021
Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran
Introduction to Various Topics in Quantum Physics	Oct. 2020
Inter Disciplinary Schools	Tehran, Iran
Introduction to Cosmology	Oct. 2020
Inter Disciplinary Schools	Tehran, Iran
Neuroscience: From Conciseness to Memory	Sep. 2019
Sharif University of Technology	Tehran, Iran

### **Q** Research Interests

- Data Driven Cosmology
- Computational Cosmology and Astrophysics
- Accretion disks (Accretion efficiency)
- Active Galactic Nuclei (Quasars)
- PBH and SMBH cosmology
- Dark matter and Dark Energy
- 21cm Cosmology
- Galaxy and Star Formation
- Large Scale Structure
- Epoch of Re-ionization
- Intergalactic Mediums
- Negative Mass Cosmology
- Interactive Dark Matter and Dark Energy (IDM)

#### **♥** Skills

**Programming Languages** Python, HTML/CSS, C++

**Development Tools and Technologies** Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, SciPy, SymPy, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Git, Jupyter Notebook, WordPress, etc.

Softwares Wolfram Mathematica (xAct, etc.), Astrometrica, Microsoft Office, Adobe (Photoshop, After Effects, InDesign)

Industry Knowledge Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Statistical Data Analysis, Numerical Analysis

Markup Languages  $\mathbb{E}T_{\mathbb{F}}X$ 

. . .

**Languages** English (Full professional proficiency), Farsi (Native), Dutch (Basic), French (Basic) **Familiar with** Linux, Julia, 21cm Cosmology, BH cosmology, Negative mass Cosmology, IDM

## **P** Honors and Awards

Ranked within the top %10 in Gravity and Cosmology among my M.Sc. graduating class.	Sept. 2023
Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %15 in Physics among my B.Sc. graduating class.	Dec. 2020
Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %2 In the Iranian University Entrance Exam for Master Degree.	2021
For Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %3 In the Iranian University Entrance Exam for Bachelor Degree.	2016
For Shahid Beheshti University	Tehran, Iran
Got Through the first level of Astronomy Student Olympiad.	2015
Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	Tehran, Iran
Got Through the first level of Physics Student Olympiad.	2015
Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the Top three projects in Physics and Astrophysics Society two years in a row.	2014-2015
Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	Tehran, Iran

### Relevant Courses

### **Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification**

Coursera

by Andrew NG

### **Data Analysis Using Python**

Pazhvak Danesh

by Mahdieh Tavakoli

## Introduction to General Relativity In Mathematica Using xAct

SciSchool Institute

by Sajad Aghapoor

Graduate Cosmology (II)
by Prof. Nima Khosravi
Advanced Astrophysics (I)

Shahid Beheshti University

Grade: 4.0/4.0

Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Sadollah Nasiri Gheydari **Under-Graduate Cosmology**  Grade: 4.0/4.0 Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Nima Khosravi
Under-Graduate Astronomy & Astrophysics

Grade: 4.0/4.0

by Prof. Nima Khosravi

Shahid Beheshti University *Grade:* 4.0/4.0

**Earth in Space**by Prof. Alireza Salehipoor

Shahid Beheshti University *Grade: 4.0/4.0* 

### References

Prof. Marzieh Farhang | Associate Professor at Physics Department of Shahid Beheshti University

M.Sc. Supervisor

**■** Email: M\_farhang [at] sbu.ac.ir

Prof. Javad Taghizadeh Firouzjaee | Associate Professor at Physics Department of Khajeh Nasir Toosi University of Technology

Supervisor at Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

**Prof. Hossein Shojaei** | Assistant Professor at Physics Department of Shahid Beheshti University

M.Sc. Supervisor

**☑** Email: H\_shojaei [at] sbu.ac.ir